<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>meta on Eric Hotinger</title>
    <link>https://ehotinger.com/tags/meta/</link>
    <description>Recent content in meta on Eric Hotinger</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 06 Jul 2021 23:58:35 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://ehotinger.com/tags/meta/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Invisible</title>
      <link>https://ehotinger.com/blog/invisible/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Jul 2021 23:58:35 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ehotinger.com/blog/invisible/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve created something magical: an invisible compass. The product is not astonishing; it&amp;rsquo;s fragile and young, yet blissful. It hasn&amp;rsquo;t been announced yet, but it will be later this year. I hope you will find it equally mesmerizing.
For the last six months, I&amp;rsquo;ve worked tirelessly to offer a chance for it to succeed. It&amp;rsquo;s not my own company and I&amp;rsquo;m not getting paid some exuberant amount of money to stay committed to an arbitrary mission.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Fearless Leader</title>
      <link>https://ehotinger.com/blog/the-fearless-leader/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Sep 2020 21:43:07 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ehotinger.com/blog/the-fearless-leader/</guid>
      <description>When you are in a living hell, the moment you start thinking of yourself instead of others, you have failed.
When you think of others, you stop focusing on yourself and your own desires. You ignore the fiery hell you are in. It becomes tolerable; a mild nuisance.
Take all of the negativity and use it to shield others. Pick up the torch and run as far and fast as you can.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Give up on CI/CD</title>
      <link>https://ehotinger.com/blog/give-up-on-ci-cd/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Sep 2020 22:20:29 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ehotinger.com/blog/give-up-on-ci-cd/</guid>
      <description>Give up on your glorious vision of CI/CD. I don&amp;rsquo;t want that shit and your customers don&amp;rsquo;t either. If you break me one more time this month I will lose my fucking mind and start looking at competitors. I can afford to wait 3 months for your new features. On second thought, I don&amp;rsquo;t care if I get any new features ever again.
I&amp;rsquo;ve written software whose sole purpose was to make CI/CD better.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>