<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>papers on Eric Hotinger</title>
    <link>https://ehotinger.com/categories/papers/</link>
    <description>Recent content in papers on Eric Hotinger</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 25 Jan 2024 10:24:56 -0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ehotinger.com/categories/papers/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Papers and Books</title>
      <link>https://ehotinger.com/blog/papers-and-books/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jan 2024 10:24:56 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ehotinger.com/blog/papers-and-books/</guid>
      <description>2024 Books Endurance by Alfred Lansing Ikigai: The Japanese Secret to a Long and Happy Life by Héctor García, Francesc Miralles Clearer, Closer, Better: How Successful People See the World by Emily Balcetis Tress of the Emerald Sea: A Cosmere Novel by Brandon Sanderson Relentless: From Good to Great to Unstoppable by Tim Grover, Shari Wenk The Three-Body Problem by Cixin Liu The Dark Forest (The Three-Body Problem Series, 2) by Cixin Liu Blogs Rebuilding Netflix Video Processing Pipeline with Microservices Slack’s Migration to a Cellular Architecture Papers Job &amp;amp; Cluster Scheduling Apollo: Scalable and Coordinated Scheduling for Cloud-Scale Computing by Eric Boutin, Jaliya Ekanayake, Wei Lin, Bing Shi, and Jingren Zhou, Microsoft; Zhengping Qian, Ming Wu, and Lidong Zhou, Microsoft Research Mesos: A Platform for Fine-Grained Resource Sharing in the Data Center by Benjamin Hindman, Andy Konwinski, Matei Zaharia, Ali Ghodsi, Anthony D.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2023 Papers and Books</title>
      <link>https://ehotinger.com/blog/2023-papers-and-books/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Jan 2023 10:24:56 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ehotinger.com/blog/2023-papers-and-books/</guid>
      <description>2023 Papers &amp;amp; Books Below is a list of papers and books I&amp;rsquo;ve read in 2023 with some minor notes around each. Each section represents a general theme/category for software development.
Books Outlive: The Science and Art of Longevity by Peter Attia The Little Book of Common Sense Investing by John Bogle Never Finished by David Goggins Die With Zero by Bill Perkins How to Win Friends &amp;amp; Influence People by Dale Carnegie Four Thousand Weeks: Time Management for Mortals The Way Out by Alan Gordon, Alon Ziv Papers No Silver Bullet — Essence and Accident in Software Engineering Written in 1986!</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
