<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>availability on Eric Hotinger</title>
    <link>https://ehotinger.com/tags/availability/</link>
    <description>Recent content in availability on Eric Hotinger</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 19 Jan 2023 13:26:55 -0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ehotinger.com/tags/availability/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Operating in Grey Modes</title>
      <link>https://ehotinger.com/blog/operating-in-grey-modes/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Jan 2023 13:26:55 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ehotinger.com/blog/operating-in-grey-modes/</guid>
      <description>Grey Modes In complex distributed systems, hardware failure is inevitable. The ability to operate in a grey mode (a mode in which a system is partially working) is an important and deliberate architectural choice to consider. Ask yourself the following question: would customers be more upset to have a completely nonfunctional system, or have a subset of the functionality working? For example, if you are working on a storage layer, perhaps it would be better to serve reads even though you can&amp;rsquo;t serve writes at the same time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Availability Numbers Every Programmer Should Know</title>
      <link>https://ehotinger.com/blog/availability-numbers-every-programmer-should-know/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Jan 2023 07:22:14 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ehotinger.com/blog/availability-numbers-every-programmer-should-know/</guid>
      <description>Availability Numbers Every Programmer Should Know Availability refers to the amount of continuous uptime of a service. This is measured in a percentage, where 100% means a service has zero downtime and 0% means the service is never operational.
A service level agreement (SLA) is a commitment from a provider to a customer. When SLAs are mentioned for availability, providers will be stating their commitment to the uptime of the system, after which you are usually entitled to some form of compensation.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
