<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>books on Eric Hotinger</title>
    <link>https://ehotinger.com/categories/books/</link>
    <description>Recent content in books on Eric Hotinger</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 02 Jan 2023 10:24:56 -0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ehotinger.com/categories/books/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>2023 Papers and Books</title>
      <link>https://ehotinger.com/blog/2023-papers-and-books/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Jan 2023 10:24:56 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ehotinger.com/blog/2023-papers-and-books/</guid>
      <description>2023 Papers &amp;amp; Books Below is a list of papers and books I&amp;rsquo;ve read in 2023 with some minor notes around each. Each section represents a general theme/category for software development.
Books Outlive: The Science and Art of Longevity by Peter Attia The Little Book of Common Sense Investing Software Patterns No Silver Bullet — Essence and Accident in Software Engineering Written in 1986! Main thought is that it&amp;rsquo;s difficult to find a magnitude improvement in the software development lifecycle.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2022 Books</title>
      <link>https://ehotinger.com/blog/2022-books/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Dec 2022 10:00:34 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ehotinger.com/blog/2022-books/</guid>
      <description>2022 Papers &amp;amp; Books As 2022 comes to a close, I wanted to reflect on some of the books I&amp;rsquo;ve had the opportunity to read this year. While I&amp;rsquo;ve enjoyed all of the books I&amp;rsquo;ve read, there are a few that stand out as particularly noteworthy.
The Expectation Effect: How Your Mindset Can Change Your World was, hands down, the best book I read this year. This book delves into the power of our mindset and how it can shape our reality.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Books for the soul</title>
      <link>https://ehotinger.com/blog/books-for-the-soul/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Aug 2021 18:12:03 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ehotinger.com/blog/books-for-the-soul/</guid>
      <description>I frequently get asked what books helped me grow the most. What would you recommend that I read to get superpowers? How did you learn about that one algorithm or data structure? How did you learn so much about something for work?
The truth is, the books and experiences that I feel like helped me the most, have nothing to do with my job. I&amp;rsquo;ll recommend those below, in a stack-ranked list and I&amp;rsquo;ll also recommend the books I think helped me learn to be technical.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
