<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>professional development on Eric Hotinger</title>
    <link>https://ehotinger.com/categories/professional-development/</link>
    <description>Recent content in professional development on Eric Hotinger</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 12 Nov 2023 17:12:26 -0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ehotinger.com/categories/professional-development/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Optimizing Impact and the Realities of Principal Engineering</title>
      <link>https://ehotinger.com/blog/optimizing-impact-and-the-realities-of-principal-engineering/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Nov 2023 17:12:26 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ehotinger.com/blog/optimizing-impact-and-the-realities-of-principal-engineering/</guid>
      <description>Optimizing Impact and the Realities of Principal Engineering The problem with being a Principal Engineer is the number of opportunities. There are so many teams that need help, so which door do you go through? You have to say no or you&amp;rsquo;re going to fail. Pick the things you&amp;rsquo;re not going to do.
We often talk about the fear of missing out - but as a PE, you are doomed to the certainty of missing out.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self Discovery and Career Growth to Principal Engineering</title>
      <link>https://ehotinger.com/blog/self-discovery-and-career-growth-to-principal-engineering/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Nov 2023 17:09:37 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ehotinger.com/blog/self-discovery-and-career-growth-to-principal-engineering/</guid>
      <description>Self Discovery and Career Growth to Principal Engineering A lot of people get promoted to senior engineer, and then they ask how to go to principal. This is not how it works. For any promotion, I tell people not to worry about immediately figuring out how to get to the next level, but especially as a senior engineer. Just focus on being a really great senior engineer first. Be great at whatever level you’re currently at.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introduction to Principal and Staff Engineering</title>
      <link>https://ehotinger.com/blog/introduction-to-principal-and-staff-engineering/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Nov 2023 12:50:06 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ehotinger.com/blog/introduction-to-principal-and-staff-engineering/</guid>
      <description>Introduction to Principal and Staff Engineering As a principal engineer (PE), you’ll find out that your whispers become roars. Casual comments you make in meetings will magically transform into roadmap items. Suddenly, you have a megaphone that you’re speaking out of at all times. Many PEs are stunned at how much people believe in their ideas and how much faith they have in them.
In the last year, I saw a story from a newly minted PE.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
