<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>leadership on Eric Hotinger</title>
    <link>https://ehotinger.com/categories/leadership/</link>
    <description>Recent content in leadership on Eric Hotinger</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 09 Jan 2023 15:14:14 -0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ehotinger.com/categories/leadership/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>How to Ask and Answer Questions Effectively</title>
      <link>https://ehotinger.com/blog/how-to-ask-and-answer-questions-effectively/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jan 2023 15:14:14 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ehotinger.com/blog/how-to-ask-and-answer-questions-effectively/</guid>
      <description>A common question from junior engineers is: &amp;ldquo;how long should I wait before I ask for help?&amp;rdquo; The below post will offer guidance for junior engineers on when and how to ask effective questions. We&amp;rsquo;ll also cover guidance to senior engineers on how to answer questions from junior engineers.
This post offers advice from both sides of the coin to help provide you the perspective of your fellow engineers. Remember: you were once a junior engineer and one day you will be the senior engineer!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Invisible</title>
      <link>https://ehotinger.com/blog/invisible/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Jul 2021 23:58:35 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ehotinger.com/blog/invisible/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve created something magical: an invisible compass. The product is not astonishing; it&amp;rsquo;s fragile and young, yet blissful. It hasn&amp;rsquo;t been announced yet, but it will be later this year. I hope you will find it equally mesmerizing.
For the last six months, I&amp;rsquo;ve worked tirelessly to offer a chance for it to succeed. It&amp;rsquo;s not my own company and I&amp;rsquo;m not getting paid some exuberant amount of money to stay committed to an arbitrary mission.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Fearless Leader</title>
      <link>https://ehotinger.com/blog/the-fearless-leader/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Sep 2020 21:43:07 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ehotinger.com/blog/the-fearless-leader/</guid>
      <description>When you are in a living nightmare, the moment you start thinking of yourself instead of others, you have failed.
When you think of others, you stop focusing on yourself and your own desires. You ignore the fiery hell you are in. It becomes tolerable; a mild nuisance.
Take all of the negativity and use it to shield others. Pick up the torch and run as far and fast as you can.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
