<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>books on Eric Hotinger</title>
    <link>https://ehotinger.com/tags/books/</link>
    <description>Recent content in books on Eric Hotinger</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 26 May 2024 10:24:56 -0800</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://ehotinger.com/tags/books/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The Latest Papers, Books, and Blogs That I Have Read</title>
      <link>https://ehotinger.com/blog/papers-and-books/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 May 2024 10:24:56 -0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ehotinger.com/blog/papers-and-books/</guid>
      <description>2025 Reads Books Fourth Wing (The Empyrean, 1) by Rebecca Yarros Sage, Huntress, Lover, Queen by Mara Branscombe Dopamine Detox: A Short Guide to Remove Distractions and Get Your Brain to Do Hard Things by Thibaut Meurisse The Autistic Brain: Helping Different Kinds of Minds Succeed by Temple Grandin The Anxious Generation: How the Great Rewiring of Childhood Is Causing an Epidemic of Mental Illness by Jonathan Haidt Blogs Databases in 2024: A Year in Review by Andy Pavlo Booting Databricks VMs 7x Faster for Serverless Compute 2024 Reads Books * The Meditations of Marcus Aurelius A Sorceress Comes to Call by T.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2023 Papers and Books</title>
      <link>https://ehotinger.com/blog/2023-papers-and-books/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Jan 2023 10:24:56 -0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ehotinger.com/blog/2023-papers-and-books/</guid>
      <description>2023 Papers &amp;amp; Books Below is a list of papers and books I&amp;rsquo;ve read in 2023 with some minor notes around each. Each section represents a general theme/category for software development.&#xA;Books Outlive: The Science and Art of Longevity by Peter Attia The Little Book of Common Sense Investing by John Bogle Never Finished by David Goggins Die With Zero by Bill Perkins How to Win Friends &amp;amp; Influence People by Dale Carnegie Four Thousand Weeks: Time Management for Mortals The Way Out by Alan Gordon, Alon Ziv Papers No Silver Bullet — Essence and Accident in Software Engineering Written in 1986!</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2022 Books</title>
      <link>https://ehotinger.com/blog/2022-books/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Dec 2022 10:00:34 -0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ehotinger.com/blog/2022-books/</guid>
      <description>2022 Papers &amp;amp; Books As 2022 comes to a close, I wanted to reflect on some of the books I&amp;rsquo;ve had the opportunity to read this year. While I&amp;rsquo;ve enjoyed all of the books I&amp;rsquo;ve read, there are a few that stand out as particularly noteworthy.&#xA;The Expectation Effect: How Your Mindset Can Change Your World was, hands down, the best book I read this year. This book delves into the power of our mindset and how it can shape our reality.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Books for the soul</title>
      <link>https://ehotinger.com/blog/books-for-the-soul/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Aug 2021 18:12:03 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ehotinger.com/blog/books-for-the-soul/</guid>
      <description>I frequently get asked what books helped me grow the most. What would you recommend that I read to get superpowers? How did you learn about that one algorithm or data structure? How did you learn so much about something for work?&#xA;The truth is, the books and experiences that I feel like helped me the most, have nothing to do with my job. I&amp;rsquo;ll recommend those below, in a stack-ranked list and I&amp;rsquo;ll also recommend the books I think helped me learn to be technical.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
