<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>productivity on Eric Hotinger</title>
    <link>https://ehotinger.com/categories/productivity/</link>
    <description>Recent content in productivity on Eric Hotinger</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 04 Feb 2023 20:24:21 -0800</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://ehotinger.com/categories/productivity/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>How Do Experienced Developers Learn New Programming Languages</title>
      <link>https://ehotinger.com/blog/how-do-experienced-developers-learn-new-programming-languages/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Feb 2023 20:24:21 -0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ehotinger.com/blog/how-do-experienced-developers-learn-new-programming-languages/</guid>
      <description>How do experienced programmers learn a new programming language? I recently read through [1] - Here we go again: why is it difficult for developers to learn another programming language?. In this paper, they interviewed a large sample size of experienced developers and asked them various questions about how they learn a new programming language. Some of the takeaways and trends were pretty interesting (in bold below).&#xA;Programmers learned languages on their own Yeah, once you graduate university, chances are you won&amp;rsquo;t ever take a class to learn a new programming language again.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Practical Developer Productivity</title>
      <link>https://ehotinger.com/blog/practical-developer-productivity/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Feb 2023 10:49:13 -0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ehotinger.com/blog/practical-developer-productivity/</guid>
      <description>Practical Developer Productivity Developer productivity has been studied extensively across the last few decades because developers are typically the most expensive piece of software development. Despite decades of research, nobody has cracked the case. Moreover, most teams struggle to come up with a metric or goal to even define what it means to capture &amp;ldquo;developer productivity.&amp;rdquo;&#xA;Over the last few months, I&amp;rsquo;ve spent a significant amount of energy in the space of developer productivity for an organization of ~500 developers.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
