<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>scalability on Eric Hotinger</title>
    <link>https://ehotinger.com/categories/scalability/</link>
    <description>Recent content in scalability on Eric Hotinger</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 21 Jul 2024 09:28:22 -0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ehotinger.com/categories/scalability/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>System Design Guide: Scalable Job Schedulers &amp; Cluster Management</title>
      <link>https://ehotinger.com/blog/system-design-guide-scalable-job-schedulers-cluster-management/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Jul 2024 09:28:22 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ehotinger.com/blog/system-design-guide-scalable-job-schedulers-cluster-management/</guid>
      <description>System Design Guide: Scalable Job Schedulers &amp;amp; Cluster Management Design a cloud service where users can execute arbitrary jobs on a recurring schedule or manually.
Functional Requirements Users should be able to create/read/update/delete jobs and schedules A job is any arbitrary program/computation that a user writes. For example, I could write a program in Python that does print(&amp;quot;Hello World!&amp;quot;), or you could write one that downloads a file and uploads it into a blob storage service.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>System Design Interviews: Framework and Strategy</title>
      <link>https://ehotinger.com/blog/system-design-interviews-framework-and-strategy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Jan 2023 09:22:14 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ehotinger.com/blog/system-design-interviews-framework-and-strategy/</guid>
      <description>System Design Interviews: Framework and Strategy System design interviews are often the most difficult technical interviews and can be daunting to tackle. They require a candidate to gather requirements, deal with ambiguity, communicate, and optimize their solution using all of their computer science knowledge. To make matters worse, these interviews are open-ended with hundreds of potential variations to achieve the desired end state of a system. How could anyone expect someone to design such a complex system in only an hour of time?</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
